So, let's get started with sentiment analysis.
下面开始创建情感分析 RNN
First, I'm going to load in data from our data directory.
首先从数据目录中加载数据
In here, there are two files reviews.txt and labels.txt.
里面有两个文件：reviews.txt 和 labels.txt
These are just the text files for our movie reviews
分别代表影评数据
data and their corresponding labels, positive or negative.
和相应的标签（正面或负面）
So, I'm going to load these in and print out some of their contents.
加载这两个文件并输出其中的一些内容
Here, you can see some example review text
这是一段示例影评文本
that's talking about a comedy called bromwell high.
评论的是喜剧《Bromwell High》
And here you see some of the text and the label's file,
这些是标签文件里的文本
which just has lines positive and negative.
内容只有“positive”和“negative”
Actually, this looks like just one review and I
现在只有一条影评
want to see if I can print out more than one.
输出多条影评看看
All right. So here, I've started printing out a second review
好的这是第二条影评
here and you can see that these two are separated by new line characters,
这两个影评用换行符分开了
much like positive and negative are separated by new lines.
“positive”和“negative”也用换行符分开了
Now, we already know that we need to pre-process this data and to organize all of
我们需要预处理数据并将词汇表中的所有字词标记化
the words in our vocabulary so that we have numerical data to feed to our model later.
变成数字数据 之后才能传入模型中
Since we're using an embedding layer,
由于我们会使用一个嵌入层
we'll need to encode each word as
所以需要将每个字词表示为整数
an integer and we'll also want to clean up our data a bit.
并且需要清理数据
The first pre-processing steps I want to take are turn
第一个预处理步骤是
our text to lowercase and getting rid of extraneous punctuation.
将文本全变成小写形式并删除多余的标点
Punctuation that, in this case,
标点符号
will not really have any bearing on whether
对于将影评分类为正面还是负面影评
our review is classified as positive or negative.
没有多大的影响
Okay. So in this cell,
Ok在这个单元格中
I'm converting all my review text to
将所有影评文本转换为小写形式
lowercase and I'm getting rid of everything that is punctuation.
并删除所有标点
And I'm using a built-in Python list here,
在这里使用内置的 Python 列表
which is from string import punctuation,
from string import punctuation
and I'm going to print out what all is in there.
输出所有标点
So, punctuation is just a list of all of these punctuation characters.
punctuation 是一个包含所有这些标点字符的列表
Then for our reviews, I'm looking at every character and if
对于影评文本 我将查看每个字符
it's not and the punctuation list, I'm keeping it.
如果它不在 punctuation 列表中 则保留该字符
This gives me a version of the review text that is all text no punctuation.
返回一个没有标点的影评文本版本
So, I'm storing that in this variable all_text.
将该版本存储到变量 all_text 中
Next, I know that my reviews are separated by a new line characters slash n. So,
影评是用换行符 \n 区分的
to separate out our reviews,
所以我将在这里使用 \n 作为分隔符
I'm going to split the text into each review using slash n as the delimiter here.
将文本拆分为多个影评条目
Then I can combine all the reviews back together as one big string.
然后将所有影评连到一起 变成一个很长的字符串
Finally, I get to my end goal,
最终目标是
which is splitting that text into individual words.
将文本拆分为单个字词
So, I'll run the cell and print out the first 30 words,
运行该单元格并输出前 30 个字词
and it looks just as I expect.
结果符合预期
Essentially, the original text that I printed out
还是原来的文本
only all the punctuation is removed and we've separated everything into individual words.
但是删掉了所有的标点 并且拆分成了一个个字词
So, our data is in good shape,
准备好数据后
and by now you should know what's coming next.
你已经知道下一步该干嘛了
We have to take our word data and
我们需要获取字词数据和标签文本数据
our label text data and convert this into numerical data.
并转换为数字数据
Your first couple of exercises will be to create
下面说说前几道练习题
a dictionary vocab_to_int that can convert any unique word into an integer token.
首先需要创建一个 vocab_to_int 字典 它会将唯一字词转换为整数标记
Then using this dictionary,
然后使用该字典
I want you to create a new list of tokenized words,
新建一个标记化字词列表
all the words in our data but converted into their integer values.
其中包含所有字词对应的整数值
I'd also like it so that our dictionary maps more frequent words to lower integer tokens.
该字典需要将更频繁的字词映射到更小的整数标记
One important thing to note here is that later,
请注意
we're going to pad our input vectors with zeros.
之后我们会用零填充输入向量
So, I actually do not want zero as a word token.
所以不能将零设为字词标记
I want the tokenized values to start at one.
标记值应该从 1 开始
And so, the most common word in our vocabulary should be mapped to the integer value one.
词汇表中最常见的字词应该映射到整数值 1
So, create that dictionary,
总结下 先创建该字典
use it to tokenize our words,
使用该字典标记化字词
and then store those tokens in a list, reviews_ints.
然后将这些标记存储到 reviews_ints 列表中
Below this, I provided some code that lets you test your implementation.
下面是一些测试代码
It'll print the length of your vocabulary and it will
它将输出词汇表的长度
print the first review in your tokenized review list.
以及标记化影评列表中的第一条影评
Your next and similar task is going to be to encode our label text into numerical values.
下道练习是将标签文本变成数字值
We saw that this text was just lines of positive or negative,
这些文本只包含“positive”和“negative”内容
and I want you to create an array encoded labels
请创建一个 encoded_labels 数组
that converts the word positive to one and negative to zero.
将“positive”转换为 1 并将“negative”转换为 0
I'm not providing any testing code here,
我没有提供任何测试代码
but I encourage you to get in the habit of testing
但是建议你养成良好习惯
out your own code piece by piece as you build.
每编写一段代码都记得测试代码
It's good practice and can be as simple as
其实很简单
a few print statements to check that your data is
添加几个输出语句就搞定了
converted as you expect or that it's the correct size and so on.
可以检查数据转换是否符合预期 或者大小是否正确 等等
These checks can really save some time later on
这些测试代码之后很有用
because these code blocks really build on one another,
因为代码块都是相互关联的
and it's good to debug early and often.
要学会经常调试代码
Okay. So, try encoding all of our words and labels on your own.
Ok试着对字词和标签进行编码吧
And if you get stuck or want to check your solution,
如果遇到问题
feel free to look at the solution video next.
请观看下个 solution 视频